<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Grow Green Futures</title>
    <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Grow Green Futures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Community Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work2/</guid>
      <description>Pop-up farms have been created using stacked shipping containers to create food growing infrastructure available and accessible in the neighbourhood. Local community business around plants and vegetables has taken off quite nicely, now they earn money from selling plants, vegetables, seeds and compost just like a garden centre. To solve the problem of the litter in the area the community has developed a communal composting hub where the neighbourhood collects everyday compostable waste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perennial Orchard</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work3/</guid>
      <description>The free food project was made possible by dedicating all of the available space to growing perennial vegetables and fruits. Fruit trees lining the neighbourhood provide fruit in abundance while still facing issues with fallen fruits and gluts leading to waste. Due to food shortages in the northeast of England all the available green space and abandoned or old buildings have been converted into community spaces for growing food. A new device has been put in place in the neighbourhood to monitor and collect the life sign data of different species including plants, animals, and insects to take into account their wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood Planter Scheme</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work4/</guid>
      <description>Machines for weeding have become a household technology for urban food growers leaving ample time for them to pursue other pleasures in life. People for plant support, a scheme launched by the community arranges for neighbours or installs technology to take care of plants when the owner is on holiday this kind of plant sitting activities have become a norm for community building and sharing in the North East. The council has started a neighbourhood planter scheme that supports people in planting and maintaining the planters throughout the year because earlier people thought they didn’t have enough money, equipment, or manpower to take care of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrations and Festivals</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work5/</guid>
      <description>Swopping and bartering have become an integral part of the community because of the new digital platform which uses existing social media, helping people to communicate via video calls, connect through council-run infrastructure and share their grown surplus with the ones who would want it. To help the community become 25% self-sufficient in their food needs, empty buildings and car parks have been converted into growing spaces with the help of local organic farmers who act as visiting experts to assist in growing at this scale in the neighbourhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-owned Spaces</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work6/</guid>
      <description>All the roofs have been covered by solar panels, a combined private and public collaboration to green and clean the west end neighbourhood. This initiative has provided free electricity enough to run greenhouses and polytunnels in the backyards and backlanes supporting food growing in the neighbourhood. Making it a place of interest for visitors and tourists alike, encouraging the possibility of entrepreneurial ventures Sensor-based devices have been deployed in food growing areas to monitor intrusion and deter trespassers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Exchange</title>
      <link>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simchop.github.io/community_growing/portfolio/work1/</guid>
      <description>Experimentation by citizens is underway to determine the new climate hardy varieties of vegetables and fruits to counteract climate change effects on food growing in Britain. The community knowledge exchange organisation set up by the neighbourhood is supporting schools with growing activities and encouraging intergenerational exchange. The program connects the older to the younger generations making students important contributors to food growing initiatives. The community has developed DIY tool kits and teaching sessions for its members to become self-reliant in making soil probes and interpreting its readings about soil composition to make better decisions around growing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
